This is the example we'll use in this section,
我们将在这个部分使用的示例是
the IMDb Movie Reviews.
IMDb 影评数据库
We will be splitting them into two kinds.
我们会将这些影评划分为两类
Reviews such as what a great movie,
将“What a great movie!”等影评
which we'll classify as positive and review such as,
分类为正面影评
that was terrible which we'll classify as negative.
将“That was terrible.”分类为负面影评
For machine learning perspective,
从机器学习的角度来说
you can think of sentiment analysis are classification or a regression problem
可以将情感分析看做分类问题或递归问题
depending on whether you want to identify specific emotional categories or labels,
取决于是要确定具体的情感类别或标签
such as positive versus negative or
例如正面与负面
a real number that captures a more fine grained sentiment value.
还是表示详细情感值的实数
In either case, you start with a given corpus say of movie reviews.
在任何一种情形下 都从给定的语料库开始 例如影评
You process each review as
将每个影评看做单个文档
a individual document and extract a set of features that represents it.
提取出代表该文档的特征集
This representation can be a direct document representation such as bag of
这种表示法可以是直接文档表示法
words or TF IDF or a sequence of word vectors combined together.
例如词袋 TF IDF 或一系列单词向量组合到一起
And then you pick classify which can be anything;
然后选择一个分类器 可以是任何分类器
a decision tree, a neural network or anything you prefer.
例如决策树 神经网络 或任何其他分类器
The representation depends on what model you choose.
表示法取决于你所选的模型
Example, if you want to use an SVM to predict sentiment labels.
例如 如果要使用 SVM 预测情感标签
You can use bag of words.
可以使用词袋
But if you want to apply an RNN,
如果要应用 RNN
you'll need word vectors.
将需要单词向量
Begin appropriate loss functions such as categorical cross entry for
采用合适的损失函数训练模型 例如为分类器选择分类交叉熵
classification or mean squared error for regression to train your model.
或为递归网络选择均方误差
In more simple terms,
简而言之
here's what we'll do. We'll take a review.
我们拿出一个影评
For example, what a great movie and we'll
例如“What a great movie!”
extract the words into a One-hot encoding vector.
将单词提取为独热编码向量
The way we'll create the vector is by taking all the words from
创建该向量的方式是选择
A to zygote and locate the ones that we have in the review.
从 a 一直到 zygote 的所有单词 并找到在影评中的单词
We had a one for those entries and a zero for all the other ones.
这些条目是 1 所有其他条目是 0
And these are the vectors that we feed into our model.
这些是输入模型中的向量
That's it. Pretty simple isn't it?
就这样 很简单对吧
So the question is, what to do with repeated words?
问题是 重复单词该怎么办？
For example in this review.
例如 在下面这个影评中
Great movie, great cast, great experience.
“Great movie, great cast, great experience.”
The word great appears three times.
单词 great 出现了三次
If we One-hot encode,
如果进行独热编码
then we'll just write a one in that entry,
则在该条目中写入 1
even if the word appears three times.
即使该单词出现三次
We really only care of the word great appears to see that the review is great.
我们只关心单词 great 是否出现了 表明该评论很正面
We can also have a bag of words approach and
我们也可以采用词袋法
record the number of appearances of the word.
记录单词的出现次数
This could make sense is if a review has the word great three times,
这么做也许很合理 如果影评出现 great 三次
it could just be greater than reviews that only has the word great once, right?
比 great 只出现一次的影评肯定更正面
And finally, the classifier M as we said can be anything.
最后 分类器 M 可以是任何分类器
In the last, we've picked one for you.
我们在 Lab 中为你选择了一个分类器
But you can change it to any other classifier you want and
但是你可以将其更改为其他分类器
explore to see which ones will give you greater accuracy on this data set.
看看哪些分类器在这个数据集上的准确率更高
And that's all you need to know to start a [inaudible]. Good luck.
对于该 Lab 你只需了解这些信息 加油！